ANDY CHEN

Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution since 2014. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team. Current hold AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (AWS-CSA) and Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD) by Linux Foundation.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

EXPERIENCE

<u>Minted LLC</u>, San Francisco — *Senior Infrastructure Engineer* March 2019 - April 2020

- Authored Kafka python/typescript client library
- Owned the whole internal protocol buffer development process of compiling, testing, and deploying and drove proto3 migration by researching and designed step-by-step migration plan, leveraging GNU make, shell scripts and dockers.
- Scale Flink/Beam data pipeline from one to N cluster each running K pipelines, and prepare chaos engineering by enabling high availability mode
- Improved internal tooling and speed up Jenkins continuous testing/deployment pipelines by more than 5 times.

<u>New Internet Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Lead Site Reliability Engineer* (*SRE*) July 2018 - March 2019

- Leveraged Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distributed stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decreased responding time by 50%.
- Developed a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

Bodhi Project, San Mateo— Senior Software Engineer May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Migrated the whole React UI library from redux to MobX architecture in 4 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Built the prototype of ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the development process.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Framework: Flink/Beam,
Protocol Buffer, gRPC, Kafka

DevOps: NPM/nexus, **AWS**, **Docker/K8S**, **TravisCI/Jenkins**, GNU make, Linux script

Backend: **RESTful/GraphQL**, express.js, MongoDB/SQL, Next.js, SSR, SEO, JWT

Languages: **Nodejs expert**, **Golang**, **Python**, **PHP**, **JAVA**, **bash**

Front-End: HTML/CSS/SASS, Javascript, **React/Redux**, **MobX**, Gulp, **Webpack**, **RWD**

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

mern, open sourced mern stack boilerplate repo and with over 1K downloads and clones.

use-form-react, a react form hook made building form use in any react app.

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Mateo — *Lead Engineer turned Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

- Authored technical yellow-paper, designed and developed the end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month. Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Developed an ERC-20 compatible VentureCoin(VCN) token and successfully launched a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

Yeah Education Group, Berkeley — Lead Engineer Dec. 2015 - April 2017

 Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API. Successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

<u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Web Developer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

EDUCATION

<u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental). Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

<u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Fulltime Entrepreneur* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Led <u>BNS</u> project and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

MENTORSHIP/BLOG

Distributed Tech Salon

authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web dev, smart contract, DevOps and Arc. design topics.

<u>Group</u> on Github I founded the virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor

Reactathon, 2017 Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization

HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** with \$10K cash for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - 1st place of Uber Challenge with \$5K awards for building Teleport, an advertisement site that connects customers and businesses.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building

Connect, a radio player

controlled with Myo gesture

controller.